Brookwood Labor College Pamphlets and Documents 5455
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brookwood Labor College Pamphlets and Documents
1933-1936
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brookwood Labor College
5455
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Pamphlets, records (documents).
Pamphlets and documents concerning Brookwood Labor College programs, the school's relations with the American Federation of Labor and other union issues. Mostly ephemeral printed materials
2297090
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, June 14, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Brookwood Labor College, 1920-1938, was a two year residential school for workers, affiliated with the American Labor Education Service and held at Katonah, N.Y.
The faculty, organized as the Brookwood Labor College (Local 189 of the American Federation of Teachers, American Federation of Labor) consisted of executives and specialists from various unions, government agencies, and faculty of universities and colleges. The curriculum included courses in journalism, English, economics, science, dramatics, and various labor related issues and topics.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of pamphlets, ephemeral printed materials, and other printed documents from the Brookwood Labor College.
Materials include bulletins and announcements of courses (1927-1933); program agenda for the Brookwood Railroad Labor Institute (1926); statements and reports pertaining to the American Federation of Labor's withdrawal of support for the Brookwood program; and pamphlets and reports pertaining to workers' education, programs at Brookwood, union administration, textile and mining industries, protective labor legislation, union organizing, labor songs, and the Railroad Labor Institute.
The collection is arranged alphabetically by title.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Adult education -- United States -- Curricula; Adult education teachers; Working class -- Songs and music -- United States; Workers' education -- Miners -- United States; Workers' education -- Railroads -- United States; Workers' education -- Textile workers -- United States; Workers' education -- United States; American Federation of Labor; Brookwood Labor College
2297090
- As Others See Us, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: As Others See Us, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By A. J. Muste. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: As Others See Us, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By A. J. Muste. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- Brickbats and Bouquets on Brookwood Labor College, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Brickbats and Bouquets on Brookwood Labor College, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Item is in English.
- Brookwood, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Brookwood: The Only Resident Trade Union Educational Institution in the United States, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Brookwood Labor Cooperating Committee. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Brookwood, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Brookwood Labor College. Item is in English.
- Brookwood: Labor's Own School, 1926; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Brookwood: Labor's Own School, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: Brookwood: Labor's Own School, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Brookwood Labor College. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Brookwood: Labor's Own School, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Brookwood Labor College. Copy 3. Item is in English.
- Brookwood Labor College, 1926; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Brookwood Labor College, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bulletin and Announcement on Labor Courses, 1927-1933; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Bulletin and Announcement of Courses, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Bulletin and Announcement of Courses, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Bulletin and Announcement of Courses, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Bulletin and Announcement of Courses, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Chautauqua Songs, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Chautauqua Songs, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Fifteenth Anniversary, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Fifteenth Anniversary Celebration of Brookwood, Labor's Own School, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Brookwood Labor College. January 18, 1936. Frank's Hofbrau, New York, NY. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Fifteenth Anniversary Celebration of Brookwood, Labor's Own School, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Brookwood Labor College. January 18, 1936. Frank's Hofbrau, New York, NY. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Brookwood, Labor's Own School: Fifteenth Anniversary Review, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: Brookwood, Labor's Own School: Fifteenth Anniversary Review, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The Injunction Against Brookwood, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: The Injunction Against Brookwood, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Brookwood Board of Directors. Item is in English.
- Institutes, 1925-1927; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Brookwood Labor Institute, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Brookwood Labor College. August 9-22, 1925. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Textile Institute, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Brookwood Labor College. July 12-17, 1926. Auspices of United Textile Workers of America. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Giant Power Instititute, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Brookwood Labor College. July 19-31, 1926. Auspices International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Second Annual Railroad Labor Institute, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Brookwood Labor College. August 1-14, 1926. Auspices Railway Employes' Department of A.F. of L. and International R.R. Labor Unions. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Program: Railroad Labor Institute, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 6: Women's Auxiliary Institute, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Brookwood Labor College. July 24-30, 1927. Initiated by Educational Department Ladies' Auxiliary, International Association of Machinists. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Brookwood Labor Institute, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Brookwood Labor College. August 1-13, 1927. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Brookwood Railroad Labor Institute, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Brookwood Labor College. August 2-8, 1925. Item is in English.
- Introduction to Labor Problems, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Introduction to Labor Problesm, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Joel Seidman. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Introduction to Labor Problesm, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Joel Seidman. Revised edition. Item is in English.
- Muste, A. J., 1927-1929; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: The Kind of Unionism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 2: Labor: Between the Devil and the Deep Blue Sea, or What Happens When the Union Cooperates With Management, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Pollack, Katherine H., 1932; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: How a Trade Union is Run, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By Katherine H. Pollak. Brookwood Labor Pamphlets. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Important Union Methods, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 3: Important Union Methods, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By Katherine H. Pollak. Brookwood Labor Pamphlets. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: What A Union Did For The Coal Miners, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Still More About Brookwood, 1929; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Still More About Brookwood College, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By A. J. Muste. A reply to a statement issued by President William Green of the American Federation of Labor on January 26, 1929. Item is in English.
- Strikes Under the New Deal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Strikes Under the New Deal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    By Maurice Goldbloom; John Herling; Joel Seidman; Elizabeth Yard; Joseph Schlossberg. Item is in English.
- Syllabi, 1925-1927; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Syllabus: History of Civilization, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 2: Syllabus: First Year Social Economics, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 3: Syllabus: First Year Sociology, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Twelfth Anniversary Review, 1933; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Twelfth Anniversary Review, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    By Brookwood Fellowship Bazaar. December 2-4, 1933. Irving Plaza, New York, NY. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Twelfth Anniversary Review, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    By Brookwood Fellowship Bazaar. December 2-4, 1933. Irving Plaza, New York, NY. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- Where Brookwood Stands Now, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Where Brookwood Stands Now, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    By Brookwood Board of Directors. A statement adopted by the Board of Directors of Brookwood Labor College at a meeting held in New York City, December 27, 1928. Item is in English.
- The Worker as a Consumer, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: The Worker As A Consumer, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    By Mark Starr; Helen Norton. Item is in English.
- Workers' Education Today and Tomorrow, 1933; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Workers' Education Today and Tomorrow, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    By Brookwood Fellowship Bazaar. December, 8-10, 1933. Yorkville Casino, New York City. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Workers' Education Today and Tomorrow, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    By Brookwood Fellowship Bazaar. December, 8-10, 1933. Yorkville Casino, New York City. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Workers' Education Today and Tomorrow, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    By Brookwood Fellowship Bazaar. December, 8-10, 1933. Yorkville Casino, New York City. Copy 3. Item is in English.
- Working For Labor Legislation, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Working For Labor Education, Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
    By Abraham Lefkowitz. Item is in English.